Adam Tilly

19884 Farnham Rd N Forest Lake, MN 55025

Phone: (612)236-6092 Tillyjadam@gmail.com

Profile

Enjoy engineering, eager to learn, punctual, dedicated, excellent time management skills, good with deadlines, goal oriented, organized, strong problem solving skills, experienced with Microsoft Office suite, 4 years of Pro-Engineer/Creo Experience, Solidworks CSWP, drive for designing products and systems.

Education

North Dakota State University

Dec. 2013

Mechanical Engineering, Bachelor of Science Degree

Experience

Applied Engineering Inc

June 2019-Current

7077 Northland Circle North, Suite 110, Brooklyn Park, MN 55428

Design Engineer II

Assisted customers in their design engineering needs

- Assist a design team in reverse engineering an electrical connector product line and also designing production fixtures to assist in assembling the connectors.
- Designed C1D1 routing through paint booth for electrical and pneumatic lines
- Used Solidworks for 3D representation of design quotes on aerospace automated systems.
- Created a crane frame model in Solidworks for seismic FEA testing to be done.
- Utilized Solidworks configurations and design tables to design new reverse engineered product and production
- Designed mechanical components for automated assembly machines

Rosenbauer Minnesota

5181 260th St, Wyoming MN 55092

Design Engineer

June 2018- June 2019

Responsible for the design of piece parts on a firetruck body and ordering special parts

- Designed ladders, ladder and tool storage, SCBA bottle storage and any other odd special part a customer wants
- Specify water pumps, foam systems, and special parts to order

Bill of Material Specialist

Feb. 2015-June 2018

Created Bills of Materials for custom firetrucks based on specifications given by the customer and also worked with other projects.

- Responsible for understanding and giving purchasing order information for any system that a customer may want.
- Participated in a Leadership Development Program (2018)
- Increased Excel abilities while developing an spreadsheet that calculated the weight distribution per axel for proposed firetrucks
- Learned how to work with a custom product and working with the flow of information to and from a customer through a sales team

RFA Engineering, Engineer I

Jan. 2014-Feb. 2015

Aug. 2011-Dec. 2013

Jan. 2011-Aug. 2011

June 2010-Dec.2010

12986 Valley View Road, Eden Prairie, MN 55344

Designed wire harness routing, air systems for large commercial engine applications and hydraulic routings on surface drills for Caterpillar

- Learned to come up with more than one concept to solve a problem based on possible short comings of other concepts to proactively come to solutions if the concepts do not meet design criteria
- Learned how to model complex castings using surfaces for castings

Internships

Case New Holland, Design Engineer Intern

Bobcat Company, Design Engineering Co-Op

Trail King Industries Inc, Manufacturing Intern

Additional Experiences

• On the board of a Non Profit Mind Over Matter